{
	"History": [
		{
			"question": "In what year did the Berlin Wall fall?",
			"answers": ["1989", "1991", "1987", "1993"],
			"correctAnswer": "1989"
		},
		{
			"question": "The first Roman emperor to become a Christian was:",
			"answers": ["Constantine", "Augustus", "Julius Caesar", "Nero"],
			"correctAnswer": "Constantine"
		},
		{
			"question": "According to ancient legends, who founded Rome?",
			"answers": [
				"Romulus and Remus",
				"Julius Caesar",
				"Augustus",
				"Marcus Aurelius"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Romulus and Remus"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which civilization was responsible for the construction of Machu Picchu?",
			"answers": ["Aztecs", "Mayans", "Incas", "Inuit"],
			"correctAnswer": "Incas"
		},
		{
			"question": "Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize?",
			"answers": [
				"Marie Curie",
				"Mother Teresa",
				"Margaret Thatcher",
				"Indira Gandhi"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Marie Curie"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of these countries was not a part of the Soviet Union?",
			"answers": ["Ukraine", "Georgia", "Poland", "Belarus"],
			"correctAnswer": "Poland"
		},
		{
			"question": "By what other name is the Eastern Roman Empire known?",
			"answers": [
				"The Byzantine Empire",
				"The Ottoman Empire",
				"The Persian Empire",
				"The Holy Roman Empire"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "The Byzantine Empire"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which country was the first to send a satellite into space?",
			"answers": ["Russia", "USA", "China", "France"],
			"correctAnswer": "Russia"
		},
		{
			"question": "Who was the first explorer to circumnavigate the globe?",
			"answers": [
				"Christopher Columbus",
				"Vasco da Gama",
				"Magellan",
				"Francis Drake"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Magellan"
		},
		{
			"question": "What was the name of the document that established the United Nations?",
			"answers": [
				"The Treaty of Versailles",
				"The Geneva Convention",
				"The Charter of the United Nations",
				"The Magna Carta"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "The Charter of the United Nations"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the goddess of victory in Greek mythology?",
			"answers": ["Nike", "Puma", "Adidas", "Aphrodite"],
			"correctAnswer": "Nike"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many operas did Beethoven compose?",
			"answers": ["1", "26", "165", "7"],
			"correctAnswer": "1"
		},
		{
			"question": "What philosopher said \"I think, therefore I am\"?",
			"answers": ["Descartes", "Plato", "Aristotle", "Socrates"],
			"correctAnswer": "Descartes"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of these is not one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?",
			"answers": [
				"The Great Library of Alexandria",
				"Colossus of Rhodes",
				"Lighthouse of Alexandria",
				"Temple of Artemis"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "The Great Library of Alexandria"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of these is not a Greek god or goddess?",
			"answers": ["Aphrodite", "Hera", "Athena", "Loki"],
			"correctAnswer": "Loki"
		}
	],
	"Entertainment": [
		
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es la ciudad más grande en la región Costa de Ecuador?",
				"answers": ["Guayaquil", "Manta", "Portoviejo", "Machala"],
				"correctAnswer": "Guayaquil"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es el puerto más importante de la región Costa?",
				"answers": ["Puerto de Guayaquil", "Puerto de Manta", "Puerto de Esmeraldas", "Puerto de Machala"],
				"correctAnswer": "Puerto de Guayaquil"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es la playa más conocida en la región Costa de Ecuador?",
				"answers": ["Salinas", "Montañita", "Atacames", "Bahía de Caráquez"],
				"correctAnswer": "Salinas"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué ciudad es conocida como la 'Capital Banquera del Ecuador'?",
				"answers": ["Guayaquil", "Quito", "Cuenca", "Machala"],
				"correctAnswer": "Guayaquil"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué provincia de la región Costa es conocida por su producción de cacao?",
				"answers": ["Los Ríos", "Guayas", "Manabí", "Esmeraldas"],
				"correctAnswer": "Los Ríos"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿En qué ciudad se encuentra el malecón 2000?",
				"answers": ["Guayaquil", "Manta", "Portoviejo", "Machala"],
				"correctAnswer": "Guayaquil"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es el principal río que atraviesa la ciudad de Guayaquil?",
				"answers": ["Río Guayas", "Río Daule", "Río Babahoyo", "Río Esmeraldas"],
				"correctAnswer": "Río Guayas"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué ciudad es famosa por su Carnaval en la región Costa?",
				"answers": ["Salinas", "Guayaquil", "Manta", "Esmeraldas"],
				"correctAnswer": "Salinas"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es la ciudad conocida por su producción de camarón en la región Costa?",
				"answers": ["Machala", "Guayaquil", "Manta", "Portoviejo"],
				"correctAnswer": "Machala"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué isla turística se encuentra en la región Costa de Ecuador?",
				"answers": ["Isla de la Plata", "Isla Galápagos", "Isla Santa Cruz", "Isla San Cristóbal"],
				"correctAnswer": "Isla de la Plata"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es la ciudad principal de la provincia de Manabí?",
				"answers": ["Portoviejo", "Manta", "Chone", "Jipijapa"],
				"correctAnswer": "Portoviejo"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué ciudad es conocida por su festival de la marimba en la región Costa?",
				"answers": ["Esmeraldas", "Guayaquil", "Manta", "Machala"],
				"correctAnswer": "Esmeraldas"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es la principal actividad económica de la ciudad de Manta?",
				"answers": ["Pesca", "Agricultura", "Turismo", "Ganadería"],
				"correctAnswer": "Pesca"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Qué ciudad costera es famosa por el surf en Ecuador?",
				"answers": ["Montañita", "Salinas", "Atacames", "Bahía de Caráquez"],
				"correctAnswer": "Montañita"
			},
			{
				"question": "¿Cuál es el nombre de la reserva natural en la región Costa conocida por sus manglares?",
				"answers": ["Reserva Ecológica Manglares Churute", "Parque Nacional Cajas", "Reserva de Producción Faunística Chimborazo", "Parque Nacional Yasuní"],
				"correctAnswer": "Reserva Ecológica Manglares Churute"
			}
		
		
	],
	"Geography": [
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál es el volcán ubicado en el centro de la Sierra ecuatoriana?",
			"answers": ["Cotopaxi", "Tungurahua", "Chimborazo", "Antisana"],
			"correctAnswer": "Chimborazo"
		},
		
		{
			"question": "¿Qué clima predominante se encuentra en la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Tropical", "Húmero", "Templado y frío", "Seco"],
			"correctAnswer": "Templado y frío"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Qué lenguas indígenas se hablan en la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Quechua", "Shuar", "Inglés", "Español"],
			"correctAnswer": "Quechua"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Qué parque nacionales se encuentran en la Sierra?",
			"answers": [
				"Parque Nacional Machalilla", 
				"Parque Nacional Sangay", 
				"Parque Nacional Cerro Blanco", 
				"Reserva Ecológica Manglares Churute"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Parque Nacional Sangay"
		},

		{
			"question": "¿Cuál es la principal zona agrícola de la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Sierra Sur", "Sierra Central", "Sierra Norte", "Esmeraldas"],
			"correctAnswer": "Sierra Central"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Qué provincia conforma la región Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Pastaza", "Los Ríos", "Azuay", "Tena"],
			"correctAnswer": "Azuay"
		},

		{
			"question": "¿A qué provincia se le conoce como la tierra de las flores y las frutas?",
			"answers": ["Riobamba", "Cañar", "Ambato", "Guaranda"],
			"correctAnswer": "Ambato"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cómo se llama el famoso mercado indígena en Otavalo?",
			"answers": ["Plaza de los Ponchos", "Atuntaqui", "San Juan", "San Antonio"],
			"correctAnswer": "Plaza de los Ponchos"
		},


		{
			"question": "¿Qué cordillera atraviesa la región Sierra?",
			"answers": [
				"La cordillera de las Montañas Rocosas ", 
				"La cordillera de los Alpes", 
				"La cordillera de los Andes", 
				"La cordillera de los Pirineos"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "La cordillera de los Andes"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál es las principal actividad económica de la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Explotación de crudo", "Pesca", "Minería", "Agricultura"],
			"correctAnswer": "Agricultura"
		},


		{
			"question": "En qué provincia se encuentra el punto más alto de Ecuador",
			"answers": ["Guayas", "Chimborazo", "Cotopaxi", "Quevedo"],
			"correctAnswer": "Chimborazo"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál es el principal lago en la Sierra de Ecuador?",
			"answers": ["San Pablo", "Yambo", "Colta", "Aguarico"],
			"correctAnswer": "San Pablo"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál es el principal producto de exportación en la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Papas", "Rosas", "Mariscos", "Ropa"],
			"correctAnswer": "Rosas"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Qué ciudad es conocida como la Atenas del Ecuador?",
			"answers": ["Imbabura", "Cuenca", "Manta", "Zamora"],
			"correctAnswer": "Cuenca"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Qué recurso es esencial para la agricultura en la Sierra?",
			"answers": ["Abono", "agua de deshielo", "Papel", "Gasolina"],
			"correctAnswer": "Agua de deshielo"
		}
	],
	"Science": [
		{
			"question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
			"answers": ["Au", "Ag", "Cu", "Fe"],
			"correctAnswer": "Au"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the triangle that has three equal sides called?",
			"answers": ["Equilateral", "Isosceles", "Scalene", "Right"],
			"correctAnswer": "Equilateral"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is an oviparous?",
			"answers": [
				"An animal that lays eggs",
				"An animal that gives birth",
				"An animal that flies",
				"An animal that lives in the water"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "An animal that lays eggs"
		},
		{
			"question": "Cartography is the study of what?",
			"answers": ["Maps", "Cars", "Cats", "Carpets"],
			"correctAnswer": "Maps"
		},
		{
			"question": "If 50 is 100%, what is 90%?",
			"answers": ["45", "10", "100", "50"],
			"correctAnswer": "45"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many legs does a fly have?",
			"answers": ["6", "4", "8", "2"],
			"correctAnswer": "6"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the smallest unit of matter?",
			"answers": ["Atom", "Molecule", "Cell", "Electron"],
			"correctAnswer": "Atom"
		},
		{
			"question": "What element do all acids contain?",
			"answers": ["Hydrogen", "Oxygen", "Helium", "Nitrogen"],
			"correctAnswer": "Hydrogen"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the process by which plants convert sunlight into energy?",
			"answers": [
				"Photosynthesis",
				"Respiration",
				"Digestion",
				"Fermentation"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Photosynthesis"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the force that pulls objects toward each other?",
			"answers": ["Gravity", "Magnetism", "Friction", "Electricity"],
			"correctAnswer": "Gravity"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the metal found in the center of the earth?",
			"answers": ["Iron", "Nickel", "Copper", "Zinc"],
			"correctAnswer": "Iron"
		},
		{
			"question": "What are diamonds made of?",
			"answers": ["Carbon", "Glass", "Silver", "Platinum"],
			"correctAnswer": "Carbon"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the process by which a solid turns into a gas without passing through the liquid state?",
			"answers": [
				"Sublimation",
				"Evaporation",
				"Condensation",
				"Freezing"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Sublimation"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the protein that gives skin, hair, and nails their strength?",
			"answers": ["Keratin", "Collagen", "Elastin", "Myosin"],
			"correctAnswer": "Keratin"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many chemical elements are there on the periodic table?",
			"answers": ["118", "92", "104", "113"],
			"correctAnswer": "118"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the first element on the periodic table?",
			"answers": ["Hydrogen", "Helium", "Lithium", "Oxygen"],
			"correctAnswer": "Hydrogen"
		},
		{
			"question": "What vitamin can be synthesized when exposed to sunlight?",
			"answers": ["Vitamin D", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin E"],
			"correctAnswer": "Vitamin D"
		},
		{
			"question": "Every how many years does Halley's Comet pass the earth?",
			"answers": ["75", "86", "96", "106"],
			"correctAnswer": "75"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the only even prime number?",
			"answers": ["2", "14", "6", "8"],
			"correctAnswer": "2"
		},
		{
			"question": "-3 + 10 ÷ 2",
			"answers": ["2", "1", "4", "3.5"],
			"correctAnswer": "2"
		},
		{
			"question": "What does the gallon measure?",
			"answers": ["Volume", "Weight", "Distance", "Time"],
			"correctAnswer": "Volume"
		},
		{
			"question": "What does the newton measure?",
			"answers": ["Force", "Weight", "Distance", "Time"],
			"correctAnswer": "Force"
		}
	],
	"Technology": [
		
			{
			  "question": "¿Por qué se llama Puyo la ciudad capital de la provincia de Pastaza?",
			  "answers": [
				"Porque Puyo significa en Kichwa 'Neblina'",
				"Porque Puyo es el nombre de un río cercano",
				"Porque Puyo fue el nombre del primer gobernador",
				"Porque Puyo significa 'Río' en Shuar"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Porque Puyo significa en Kichwa 'Neblina'"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad de la Amazonía ecuatoriana es conocida como 'La Capital de la Biodiversidad'?",
			  "answers": [
				"Tena",
				"Macas",
				"Puyo",
				"Coca"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Tena"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Cuál es la principal actividad económica de la ciudad de Coca?",
			  "answers": [
				"Turismo",
				"Agricultura",
				"Extracción de petróleo",
				"Pesca"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Extracción de petróleo"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿En qué provincia de la Amazonía ecuatoriana se encuentra la ciudad de Macas?",
			  "answers": [
				"Pastaza",
				"Morona Santiago",
				"Napo",
				"Orellana"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Morona Santiago"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Cuál es el río que pasa por la ciudad de Tena?",
			  "answers": [
				"Río Napo",
				"Río Pastaza",
				"Río Putumayo",
				"Río Aguarico"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Río Napo"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad de la Amazonía ecuatoriana es conocida por sus aguas termales?",
			  "answers": [
				"Baños",
				"Puyo",
				"Papallacta",
				"Tena"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Papallacta"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Cuál es la ciudad más grande de la provincia de Sucumbíos?",
			  "answers": [
				"Nueva Loja (Lago Agrio)",
				"Coca",
				"Tena",
				"Puyo"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Nueva Loja (Lago Agrio)"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad amazónica ecuatoriana es conocida por la fiesta de la chonta?",
			  "answers": [
				"Archidona",
				"Macas",
				"Coca",
				"Zamora"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Archidona"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad de la Amazonía ecuatoriana tiene un zoológico llamado 'El Arca'?",
			  "answers": [
				"Tena",
				"Puyo",
				"Macas",
				"Nueva Loja"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Tena"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad amazónica es conocida como la 'Puerta de la Amazonía'?",
			  "answers": [
				"Macas",
				"Puyo",
				"Tena",
				"Coca"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Macas"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Cuál es la principal festividad de la ciudad de Macas?",
			  "answers": [
				"Fiesta de la Chonta",
				"Fiesta de la Canelazo",
				"Fiesta de la Guayusa",
				"Fiesta de la Yuca"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Fiesta de la Chonta"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad amazónica ecuatoriana está cerca del Parque Nacional Yasuní?",
			  "answers": [
				"Coca",
				"Macas",
				"Puyo",
				"Tena"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Coca"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Cuál es el nombre del aeropuerto de la ciudad de Puyo?",
			  "answers": [
				"Aeropuerto General Rivadeneira",
				"Aeropuerto Río Amazonas",
				"Aeropuerto Edmundo Carvajal",
				"Aeropuerto Jumandy"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Aeropuerto Edmundo Carvajal"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿Qué ciudad amazónica ecuatoriana es conocida por su producción de cacao?",
			  "answers": [
				"Nueva Loja",
				"Macas",
				"Tena",
				"Zamora"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Zamora"
			},
			{
			  "question": "¿En qué ciudad de la Amazonía ecuatoriana se encuentra la cascada San Rafael?",
			  "answers": [
				"Tena",
				"Puyo",
				"Macas",
				"Nueva Loja"
			  ],
			  "correctAnswer": "Nueva Loja"
			}
		  ],
		  
	"Art": [
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades de Galápagos es conocida por su bahía que alberga leones marinos?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Baquerizo Moreno"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades de Galápagos es la puerta de entrada principal para turistas?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Chino",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿En cuál de las siguientes ciudades se encuentra la Estación Científica Charles Darwin?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades es la capital administrativa de Galápagos?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Baquerizo Moreno"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades está ubicada en la isla Isabela?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Villamil"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades es conocida por su tortuga gigante 'Diego'?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿En cuál de las siguientes ciudades puedes visitar el Centro de Crianza Arnaldo Tupiza?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Villamil"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades tiene acceso a la Playa de los Alemanes?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades es famosa por la playa Tortuga Bay?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿En cuál de las siguientes ciudades se encuentra el Centro de Interpretación de Galápagos?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Baquerizo Moreno"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades está situada en la isla Santa Cruz?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Ayora"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades ofrece tours a Los Túneles?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Villamil"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades tiene acceso a la Playa Mann?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Baquerizo Moreno"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿En cuál de las siguientes ciudades puedes encontrar el Muro de las Lágrimas?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Villamil"
		},
		{
			"question": "¿Cuál de las siguientes ciudades es la más grande de la isla Isabela?",
			"answers": [
				"Puerto Ayora",
				"Puerto Villamil",
				"Puerto Baquerizo Moreno",
				"Puerto Chino"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Puerto Villamil"
		}
	],
	"Space": [
		{
			"question": "What is the largest planet in our solar system?",
			"answers": ["Jupiter", "Saturn", "Uranus", "Neptune"],
			"correctAnswer": "Jupiter"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the brightest star in the night sky?",
			"answers": [
				"Sirius",
				"Proxima Centauri",
				"Betelgeuse",
				"Aldebaran"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Sirius"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the only natural satellite of Earth?",
			"answers": ["Moon", "Mars", "Venus", "Jupiter"],
			"correctAnswer": "Moon"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the first artificial satellite launched into space?",
			"answers": ["Sputnik 1", "Explorer 1", "Vanguard 1", "Vostok 1"],
			"correctAnswer": "Sputnik 1"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the speed of light approximately?",
			"answers": [
				"300,000 km/s",
				"200,000 km/s",
				"100,000 km/s",
				"400,000 km/s"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "300,000 km/s"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the largest known asteroid in our solar system?",
			"answers": ["Ceres", "Vesta", "Pallas", "Hygiea"],
			"correctAnswer": "Ceres"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the spacecraft that landed on Mars in 2021 as part of the Mars 2020 mission?",
			"answers": ["Perseverance", "Curiosity", "Opportunity", "Spirit"],
			"correctAnswer": "Perseverance"
		},
		{
			"question": "How long does it take for sunlight to reach the earth?",
			"answers": ["8 minutes", "3.5 hours", "26 seconds", "10 seconds"],
			"correctAnswer": "8 minutes"
		},
		{
			"question": "About how many stars are there in the solar system?",
			"answers": ["1", "100", "100,000", "Too many to count"],
			"correctAnswer": "1"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the most common matter in the universe?",
			"answers": ["Hydrogen", "Dark matter", "Helium", "Oxygen"],
			"correctAnswer": "Hydrogen"
		},
		{
			"question": "About what temperature is it in space?",
			"answers": ["-270°C", "-120°C", "0°C", "38°C"],
			"correctAnswer": "-270°C"
		},
		{
			"question": "Mainly which atoms do stars use in their fusion process?",
			"answers": ["Hydrogen", "Helium", "Oxygen", "Carbon"],
			"correctAnswer": "Hydrogen"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is inside a black hole in the movie \"Interstellar\"?",
			"answers": [
				"A fifth dimension",
				"A planet",
				"A spaceship",
				"Nothing"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "A fifth dimension"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the geometric figure that describes the orbit of the planets?",
			"answers": ["Ellipse", "Circle", "Circumference", "Square"],
			"correctAnswer": "Ellipse"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many moons does Mars have?",
			"answers": ["1", "2", "4", "Does not have"],
			"correctAnswer": "2"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the first man to walk on the moon?",
			"answers": [
				"Neil Armstrong",
				"Buzz Aldrin",
				"Alan Shepard",
				"Yuri Gagarin"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Neil Armstrong"
		}
	],
	"General culture": [
		{
			"question": "What part of the ship does the nautical term \"starboard\" refer to?",
			"answers": ["Right", "Left", "Front", "Back"],
			"correctAnswer": "Right"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which river runs through London?",
			"answers": ["Thames", "Seine", "Danube", "Nile"],
			"correctAnswer": "Thames"
		},
		{
			"question": "Who turns into Hulk?",
			"answers": [
				"Bruce Banner",
				"Tony Stark",
				"Peter Parker",
				"Steve Rogers"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Bruce Banner"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many players does a soccer team have on the field?",
			"answers": ["11", "10", "9", "12"],
			"correctAnswer": "11"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of these is a percussion instrument?",
			"answers": ["Drum", "Violin", "Flute", "Trumpet"],
			"correctAnswer": "Drum"
		},
		{
			"question": "What color is the \"G\" in the Google logo?",
			"answers": ["Blue", "Red", "Yellow", "Green"],
			"correctAnswer": "Blue"
		},
		{
			"question": "What holds the Oscar trophy figurine?",
			"answers": ["A sword", "A torch", "A book", "Nothing"],
			"correctAnswer": "A sword"
		},
		{
			"question": "What instrument does Sherlock Holmes play?",
			"answers": ["Violin", "Flute", "Piano", "Guitar"],
			"correctAnswer": "Violin"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is a falchion?",
			"answers": ["A sword", "A shield", "A helmet", "A spear"],
			"correctAnswer": "A sword"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many hearts does an octopus have?",
			"answers": ["3", "2", "1", "0"],
			"correctAnswer": "3"
		},
		{
			"question": "What does the Tin Woodman want in the novel \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?",
			"answers": ["A heart", "A brain", "Courage", "A home"],
			"correctAnswer": "A heart"
		},
		{
			"question": "What color is the hair of the protagonist in the anime \"Death Note\"?",
			"answers": ["Black", "Blonde", "Red", "Brown"],
			"correctAnswer": "Brown"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the name of the holy book of Islam?",
			"answers": ["Quran", "Bible", "Torah", "Vedas"],
			"correctAnswer": "Quran"
		},
		{
			"question": "How old is a lustrum?",
			"answers": ["5 years", "10 years", "15 years", "20 years"],
			"correctAnswer": "5 years"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many sides does a hexagon have?",
			"answers": ["6", "5", "7", "8"],
			"correctAnswer": "6"
		}
	]
}
